<novelConcept>
  <rejectedIdeas>
    <idea>
      A post-apocalyptic drama where survivors navigate a world ravaged by an unknown global climate disaster. 
    </idea>
    <idea>
      A historical novel set in the French Revolution with a central character who alters the course of history through unprecedented acts of courage.
    </idea>
    <idea>
      A contemporary legal drama circling the life of a prodigious lawyer gone rogue in his quest for justice after losing a controversial case.
    </idea>
  </rejectedIdeas>
  <acceptedIdea>
    A deeply moving, character-driven novel about an immigrant family's struggle for the American Dream during the Great Depression and their triumphs and trials in the face of adversity.
  </acceptedIdea>
  <title>
    Shadow of the American Dream
  </title>
  <cover>
    A silhouette of a family, hand in hand, standing against a backdrop of a dilapidated house, with an imposing skyscraper under construction soaring in the distance. The color palette is stark, using deep blacks and grays, with a single streak of golden light emanating from the horizon to represent hope.
  </cover>
  <characters>
    <character>
      <name>Alessandro Russo</name>
      <description>A wiry Italian immigrant and father who is constantly torn between his desire to provide for his family and the ruthless demands of the city.</description>
    </character>
    <character>
      <name>Maria Russo</name>
      <description>Alessandro's wife, a resilient woman who keeps the family together despite the hardships, never wavering in her faith in their shared dream.</description>
    </character>
    <character>
      <name>Luca Russo</name>
      <description>Their teenage son who struggles with his identity as a first-generation American and the burden of their dreams pinned on him.</description>
    </character>
  </characters>
  <firstSentence>
    In the year 1929, Alessandro Russo, with his wife Maria clinging tightly to his arm, stepped off the boat onto the foreign soil that spelled a new life, a new dream, and a new struggle.
  </firstSentence>
</novelConcept>